<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!--<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>-->
<!--<?xml-stylesheet href="\billres.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>-->
<!--<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill v2.8 20020720//EN" "http://xml.house.gov/bill.dtd">-->
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill v2.8 20020720//EN" "http://thomas.loc.gov/dtd/bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HD1E1E5BA6B484EA0A2C8FF8D2B554CBC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="traditional"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1586 ENR: ______Act of____</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Eleventh Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the fifth day of January, two thousand and ten</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1586</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To modernize the air traffic control system, improve the safety, reliability, and availability of transportation by air in the United States, provide for modernization of the air traffic control system, reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H374EEF8B3AE04C78A5D6869356BD8BA1" style="traditional"> 
<section id="H56DA28E74BBE4D3BAC559BF21D9B1D2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>______Act of____</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<title id="H400AC9814BAE4F4AB75F30923C30FFC4"><enum>I</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Education Jobs Fund</header> 
<section id="HE12CE878A9DE41DF905E43E5A6B2CC4D"><enum>101.</enum><header>Education Jobs Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated and there are appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise obligated for necessary expenses for an Education Jobs Fund, $10,000,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount under this heading shall be administered under the terms and conditions of sections 14001 through 14013 and title XV of division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) except as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC05059529AC47E29D91519A14A163C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF08D031C196B4FCFB7DBC3BF9C5A488D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Funds appropriated under this heading shall be available only for allocation by the Secretary of Education (in this heading referred to as the Secretary) in accordance with subsections (a), (b), (d), (e), and (f) of section 14001 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref> and subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, except that the amount reserved under such subsection (b) shall not exceed $1,000,000 and such subsection (f) shall be applied by substituting one year for two years.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76EC9A0D4BD348E09CC5E2AD25025863"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to allocating funds to States under section 14001(d) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, the Secretary shall allocate 0.5 percent to the Secretary of the Interior for schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs on the basis of the schools’ respective needs for activities consistent with this heading under such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Interior may determine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F9FD20C41494C1892586C3A339C5250"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives an allocation of funds appropriated under this heading may reserve not more than 2 percent for the administrative costs of carrying out its responsibilities with respect to those funds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB62CC20E33FA4ADDA143D57C961C133C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Awards to local educational agencies</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9FD9E2BC326E42C095C28FF671423676"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as specified in paragraph (2), an allocation of funds to a State shall be used only for awards to local educational agencies for the support of elementary and secondary education in accordance with paragraph (5) for the 2010–2011 school year (or, in the case of reallocations made under section 14001(f) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, for the 2010–2011 or the 2011–2012 school year).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31B98E5ADF0C48BF80865BE9D7AB5931"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds used to support elementary and secondary education shall be distributed through a State’s primary elementary and secondary funding formulae or based on local educational agencies’ relative shares of funds under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) for the most recent fiscal year for which data are available.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE2DB8E1DBA546C3946C55800C64296F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subsections (a) and (b) of section 14002 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref> shall not apply to funds appropriated under this heading.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F53AD93E9AA4BF9A89291A4A49791BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance with education reform assurances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of awarding funds appropriated under this heading, any State that has an approved application for Phase II of the State Fiscal Stabilization Fund that was submitted in accordance with the application notice published in the Federal Register on November 17, 2009 (74 Fed. Reg. 59142) shall be deemed to be in compliance with subsection (b) and paragraphs (2) through (5) of subsection (d) of section 14005 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2429C65C539F4E5E835457C2C8555715"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirement to use funds to retain or create education jobs</header><text>Notwithstanding section 14003(a) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, funds awarded to local educational agencies under paragraph (3)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA94B04704CE04CD388CC4BC9ED53009A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be used only for compensation and benefits and other expenses, such as support services, necessary to retain existing employees, to recall or rehire former employees, and to hire new employees, in order to provide early childhood, elementary, or secondary educational and related services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B8209E1A2C746C9B46B272D70CFC5D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be used for general administrative expenses or for other support services expenditures as those terms were defined by the National Center for Education Statistics in its Common Core of Data as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A63F86A567640319C26192809535B19"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for rainy-day funds or debt retirement</header><text>A State that receives an allocation may not use such funds, directly or indirectly, to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H889EE1ABB9BA4C29B8F39D4B8D6D1836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish, restore, or supplement a rainy-day fund;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C841C58ADE647DAAE9B126B9288EE98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supplant State funds in a manner that has the effect of establishing, restoring, or supplementing a rainy-day fund;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA3CCFB56F25407BA551665608886A00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce or retire debt obligations incurred by the State; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F25B143AD9A405F9E20BCF034C9F15F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supplant State funds in a manner that has the effect of reducing or retiring debt obligations incurred by the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA47D1E1343A44D4BD49AD6D97B0A4E6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Deadline for award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award funds appropriated under this heading not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act to States that have submitted applications meeting the requirements applicable to funds under this heading. The Secretary shall not require information in applications beyond what is necessary to determine compliance with applicable provisions of law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05DDA80CE2E14EC680CFE5AC682F11E1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Alternate distribution of funds</header><text>If, within 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a Governor has not submitted an approvable application, the Secretary shall provide for funds allocated to that State to be distributed to another entity or other entities in the State (notwithstanding section 14001(e) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) for support of elementary and secondary education, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may establish, provided that all terms and conditions that apply to funds appropriated under this heading shall apply to such funds distributed to such entity or entities. No distribution shall be made to a State under this paragraph, however, unless the Secretary has determined (on the basis of such information as may be available) that the requirements of clauses (i), (ii), or (iii) of paragraph 10(A) are likely to be met, notwithstanding the lack of an application from the Governor of that State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C233A08CD654D8B81BDB7384C700219"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Local educational agency application</header><text>Section 442 of the General Education Provisions Act shall not apply to a local educational agency that has previously submitted an application to the State under title XIV of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>. The assurances provided under that application shall continue to apply to funds awarded under this heading.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H315F7303DA244975BB4647DB325EA74F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA91D8DE726034BCD8DC05300DA02E9B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (8), the Secretary shall not allocate funds to a State under paragraph (1) unless the Governor of the State provides an assurance to the Secretary that—</text> 
<clause id="HF6E7CC08AF3049B2A3B3AAFEDE100B59"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for State fiscal year 2011, the State will maintain State support for elementary and secondary education (in the aggregate or on the basis of expenditures per pupil) and for public institutions of higher education (not including support for capital projects or for research and development or tuition and fees paid by students) at not less than the level of such support for each of the two categories, respectively, for State fiscal year 2009;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFC534446F4F24AAA92A0B0D563E0E30B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for State fiscal year 2011, the State will maintain State support for elementary and secondary education and for public institutions of higher education (not including support for capital projects or for research and development or tuition and fees paid by students) at a percentage of the total revenues available to the State that is equal to or greater than the percentage provided for each of the two categories, respectively, for State fiscal year 2010; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0859D4E0901D4AFAB0B670D0A7633303"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State in which State tax collections for calendar year 2009 were less than State tax collections for calendar year 2006, for State fiscal year 2011 the State will maintain State support for elementary and secondary education (in the aggregate) and for public institutions of higher education (not including support for capital projects or for research and development or tuition and fees paid by students)—</text> 
<subclause id="HE4A02CB7281B4DB2AA5EA9BD46EDC4A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at not less than the level of such support for each of the two categories, respectively, for State fiscal year 2006; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBCA555989DE544938D25EA4CB3EDA16D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at a percentage of the total revenues available to the State that is equal to or greater than the percentage provided for each of the two categories, respectively, for State fiscal year 2006.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91F3898BF36F40DF9017DA54DCE64C68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 14005(d)(1) and subsections (a) through (c) of section 14012 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref> shall not apply to funds appropriated under this heading.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07C306F059814F41B84951260C52E784"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Additional requirements for the State of Texas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following requirements shall apply to the State of Texas:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF53F234D08D2421EBCBF53E62D2BA606"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (3)(B), funds used to support elementary and secondary education shall be distributed based on local educational agencies’ relative shares of funds under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) for the most recent fiscal year which data are available. Funds distributed pursuant to this paragraph shall be used to supplement and not supplant State formula funding that is distributed on a similar basis to part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F76DCADA4D244EE8EF5036F65D0957F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not allocate funds to the State of Texas under paragraph (1) unless the Governor of the State provides an assurance to the Secretary that the State will for fiscal years 2011, 2012, and 2013 maintain State support for elementary and secondary education at a percentage of the total revenues available to the State that is equal to or greater than the percentage provided for such purpose for fiscal year 2011 prior to the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H476F8D0E246C4560925770E2F3527FE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (8), no distribution shall be made to the State of Texas or local education agencies therein unless the Governor of Texas makes an assurance to the Secretary that the requirements in paragraphs (11)(A) and (11)(B) will be met, notwithstanding the lack of an application from the Governor of Texas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></title> 
<title id="H24C965CA79314C69AB4C9A86165802CB"><enum>II</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">State Fiscal Relief and Other Provisions; Revenue Offsets </header> 
<subtitle id="HBFA87408439D4D0BA3A7BC4F76A8808C"><enum>A</enum><header>State Fiscal Relief and Other Provisions</header> 
<section id="H32C5F3BD373745F5B9DBC8422B62A2A5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Extension of ARRA increase in FMAP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5001 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H01B386F37BF84E07BFDEF9784B2777E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(3), by striking <quote>first calendar quarter</quote> and inserting <quote>first 3 calendar quarters</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82A8ADA82FC64864AD373C56BC5AF94E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD42661CF4D2D43A790528AA9D3DD4C68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCD78D7BB7364ED78E2D98BD94552A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E2ABF5CC5CB42678B6FDBE384F16336" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H81CB0791C3D64ADAA9C4203A0E9BD11D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Phase-down of general increase</header> 
<subparagraph id="H741549701FB0405C8A526D2E015852F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Second quarter of fiscal year 2011</header><text>For each State, for the second quarter of fiscal year 2011, the FMAP percentage increase for the State under paragraph (1) or (2) (as applicable) shall be 3.2 percentage points.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98275244F1754927B1471986C5764BA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Third quarter of fiscal year 2011</header><text>For each State, for the third quarter of fiscal year 2011, the FMAP percentage increase for the State under paragraph (1) or (2) (as applicable) shall be 1.2 percentage points.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H80E4780C55074E2693EA4B743C6CFA97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H336CA5F641A043A9831FA67CD6EA6C39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>July 1, 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 2011</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H430CD5E5982C437E824369C20302450B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)(i), by striking <quote>July 1, 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 2011</quote> each place it appears; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CECE987EC304AB09BE2CC85DDCC4B38"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)(C)(ii), by striking <quote>the 3-consecutive-month period beginning with January 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>any 3-consecutive-month period that begins after December 2009 and ends before January 2011</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56F1258DE2814402B629AC03342409B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FFD53216E8340BB8B55F3AB20A72D6D" style="OLC"> 
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subsection">Notwithstanding paragraph (5), effective for payments made on or after January 1, 2010, the increases in the FMAP for a State under this section shall apply to payments under title XIX of such Act that are attributable to expenditures for medical assistance provided to nonpregnant childless adults made eligible under a State plan under such title (including under any waiver under such title or under section 1115 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>)) who would have been eligible for child health assistance or other health benefits under eligibility standards in effect as of December 31, 2009, of a waiver of the State child health plan under the title XXI of such Act.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F67C64351394D6A98F47A7A06519631"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H407AD418C1024AA0932A8C377803C504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>September 30, 2011</quote> and inserting <quote>March 31, 2012</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5175E65BBF2E44E49BFFE9359AABD2BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>of such Act</quote> after <quote>1923</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5A5E7A1C4A043C8AB53ADD0876A167A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64BA762B01EB4EA481E09110FB6944B8" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H64279BD0CD014EE393507E92E96D405E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification by chief executive officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional Federal funds shall be paid to a State as a result of this section with respect to a calendar quarter occurring during the period beginning on January 1, 2011, and ending on June 30, 2011, unless, not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the chief executive officer of the State certifies that the State will request and use such additional Federal funds.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2A92A978A5F4BDD8B7837FD4AF07221"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(3), by striking <quote>December 31, 2010</quote> and inserting <quote>June 30, 2011</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E616A56243047A89B75D0A2C252198B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Treatment of certain drugs for computation of Medicaid AMP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as if included in the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>, section 1927(k)(1)(B)(i)(IV) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)(1)(B)(i)(IV)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2503(a)(2)(B) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref> and section 1101(c)(2) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>, unless the drug is an inhalation, infusion, instilled, implanted, or injectable drug that is not generally dispensed through a retail community pharmacy; and</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC1D826C5830B4E0CAE3E1343CC1658F0"><enum>203.</enum><header>Sunset of temporary increase in benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(a) of title I of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref> (123 Stat. 120), as amended by section 4262 of this Act, is amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF580B23A6CB249D28A2FE74A0D3A87F1" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H2C54F912C4DE48A3A968EC5F689048D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority provided by this subsection shall terminate after March 31, 2014.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></subtitle> 
<subtitle id="HF3FD27E065F949D09176790BD220DC4D"><enum>B</enum><header>Revenue Offsets</header> 
<section id="H7AE7329606F04194A7BF34CD25116C24" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>211.</enum><header>Rules to prevent splitting foreign tax credits from the income to which they relate</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFFDB384910FB4BF0A96213E6D225E525"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part III of subchapter N of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3FBDC46D0BD4196BD3D90E93E1015DA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCB56C15C523740C49A673A069560B9E9"><enum>909.</enum><header>Suspension of taxes and credits until related income taken into account</header> 
<subsection id="HFC03AF9150C2441BBD7DD7C8EC4CAC8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is a foreign tax credit splitting event with respect to a foreign income tax paid or accrued by the taxpayer, such tax shall not be taken into account for purposes of this title before the taxable year in which the related income is taken into account under this chapter by the taxpayer.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H538AD26FF9394C89B852E126501FE81B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules with respect to section 902 corporations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is a foreign tax credit splitting event with respect to a foreign income tax paid or accrued by a section 902 corporation, such tax shall not be taken into account—</text> 
<paragraph id="H546C81D285014A7CA84C4DCD8A60035E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for purposes of section 902 or 960, or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD0E4715EC354D43B7FD0ED5482A98C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for purposes of determining earnings and profits under section 964(a),</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">before the taxable year in which the related income is taken into account under this chapter by such section 902 corporation or a domestic corporation which meets the ownership requirements of subsection (a) or (b) of section 902 with respect to such section 902 corporation.</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98F6E1475EA94C1D8582F55236E521E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4209C7515F054632B3E9405F87E54124"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to partnerships, etc</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a partnership, subsections (a) and (b) shall be applied at the partner level. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, a rule similar to the rule of the preceding sentence shall apply in the case of any S corporation or trust.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEACDB571173490E9580488CA8DF4540"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of foreign taxes after suspension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any foreign income tax not taken into account by reason of subsection (a) or (b), except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such tax shall be so taken into account in the taxable year referred to in such subsection (other than for purposes of section 986(a)) as a foreign income tax paid or accrued in such taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0561F0CF2DF048288539EF95E3839F47"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF90169A174F44B68B9F2A00CECC49CDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign tax credit splitting event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a foreign tax credit splitting event with respect to a foreign income tax if the related income is (or will be) taken into account under this chapter by a covered person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H365FD4054BB749D580D5716E45DB614B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign income tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign income tax</quote> means any income, war profits, or excess profits tax paid or accrued to any foreign country or to any possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H832D4A25DD3A4D559E563A37DBC76AFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related income</header><text>The term <quote>related income</quote> means, with respect to any portion of any foreign income tax, the income (or, as appropriate, earnings and profits) to which such portion of foreign income tax relates.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB95CFF89E15944D29D020F03431CDB2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <quote>covered person</quote> means, with respect to any person who pays or accrues a foreign income tax (hereafter in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>payor</quote>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9678D78D5BEA43298BECA601791B84A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any entity in which the payor holds, directly or indirectly, at least a 10 percent ownership interest (determined by vote or value),</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE437A12290AB434C88201D9CC1B0A9DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person which holds, directly or indirectly, at least a 10 percent ownership interest (determined by vote or value) in the payor,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D0B75753EF942C2BDB9E9BFFB2AD840"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person which bears a relationship to the payor described in section 267(b) or 707(b), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H566AD5D2D4594154B243102F2D3E52C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other person specified by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H657116E966A841BDAA4B62ADCFBA1C0D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Section 902 corporation</header><text>The term <quote>section 902 corporation</quote> means any foreign corporation with respect to which one or more domestic corporations meets the ownership requirements of subsection (a) or (b) of section 902.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DCD66DF3C424B688AF2DF9CDD7C77FD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance which provides—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2288A60B73744ABBAFB9EB5D1BBB4432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate exceptions from the provisions of this section, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE38B2EF7E3B42E1ACF655CF2B549D9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the proper application of this section with respect to hybrid instruments.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F5CC0B5459E43B3BD3DE2C535FA2B25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart A of part III of subchapter N of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H845EA532C8B74440BD525946842B3843" style="OLC"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HE3FBDC46D0BD4196BD3D90E93E1015DA" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HCB56C15C523740C49A673A069560B9E9" level="section">Sec. 909. Suspension of taxes and credits until related income taken into account.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H2B18DEB078ED4E77A99D62D809D64601"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA3B83C77B06A448E9765A7E72A1EA97B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign income taxes (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/909">section 909(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section) paid or accrued in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HDC4E4E6D6A7E40D58A12D6B371511D89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foreign income taxes (as so defined) paid or accrued by a section 902 corporation (as so defined) in taxable years beginning on or before such date (and not deemed paid under section 902(a) or 960 of such Code on or before such date), but only for purposes of applying sections 902 and 960 with respect to periods after such date.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Section 909(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section, shall not apply to foreign income taxes described in paragraph (2).</continuation-text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAEEA6F325F994913B51D7972750F79F9"><enum>212.</enum><header>Denial of foreign tax credit with respect to foreign income not subject to United States taxation by reason of covered asset acquisitions</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H777888B743114B2A8475D785DE677CF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/901">Section 901</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (m) as subsection (n) and by inserting after subsection (l) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5ADD78860DE947BE81B2EE2508FB2D73" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H2D0A1E4937C248ACAFFC460D82EE0D60"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Denial of foreign tax credit with respect to foreign income not subject to United States taxation by reason of covered asset acquisitions</header> 
<paragraph id="HCF212593CBA7443C95DEECD9212D7B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a covered asset acquisition, the disqualified portion of any foreign income tax determined with respect to the income or gain attributable to the relevant foreign assets—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H97F308BFE3A948769C46A83B47033889"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be taken into account in determining the credit allowed under subsection (a), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3CA9772E4E4486A806389EB66D0036B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a foreign income tax paid by a section 902 corporation (as defined in section 909(d)(5)), shall not be taken into account for purposes of section 902 or 960.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A9EE1B8133F4E3CBF1C1FCAC7A767A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered asset acquisition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered asset acquisition</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8BA124280FF34141BAD994B754D8AC9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a qualified stock purchase (as defined in section 338(d)(3)) to which section 338(a) applies,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H842D2229857A4D76ABAAA1DD17AA209B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any transaction which—</text> 
<clause id="H01F7BA68FEB94A92A86C89C560231291"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is treated as an acquisition of assets for purposes of this chapter, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6A7BD96ABB24FFFA54E63B6C13CEFFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is treated as the acquisition of stock of a corporation (or is disregarded) for purposes of the foreign income taxes of the relevant jurisdiction,</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8858764BBFE94D5890B5E3F0C9324F00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any acquisition of an interest in a partnership which has an election in effect under section 754, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5325B328EFC7424CB05E1948BECA106A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the extent provided by the Secretary, any other similar transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAE3FAE0FB35474B9D81628871161D3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disqualified portion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7C3227E94DC847E9BA40C019C17796CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>disqualified portion</quote> means, with respect to any covered asset acquisition, for any taxable year, the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text> 
<clause id="H33CB94DBCD684F84A5647B9DFEA5701C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate basis differences (but not below zero) allocable to such taxable year under subparagraph (B) with respect to all relevant foreign assets, divided by</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD329829DFC85487D95CDB6A13AD01FCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the income on which the foreign income tax referred to in paragraph (1) is determined (or, if the taxpayer fails to substantiate such income to the satisfaction of the Secretary, such income shall be determined by dividing the amount of such foreign income tax by the highest marginal tax rate applicable to such income in the relevant jurisdiction).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F6472E441A34E1AA5951E2F1AB8217E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of basis difference</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i)—</text> 
<clause id="H2F9DD2A0BA774EA9A654017FC76EB33B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The basis difference with respect to any relevant foreign asset shall be allocated to taxable years using the applicable cost recovery method under this chapter.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8E8B080E9CD941B2B201D31DA628A034"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule for disposition of assets</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of the disposition of any relevant foreign asset—</text> 
<subclause id="H69E986D2C96C41E789B359065A69F4EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the basis difference allocated to the taxable year which includes the date of such disposition shall be the excess of the basis difference with respect to such asset over the aggregate basis difference with respect to such asset which has been allocated under clause (i) to all prior taxable years, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6A4D99BD0C3640CFAFD45EB3E9364719"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no basis difference with respect to such asset shall be allocated under clause (i) to any taxable year thereafter.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF274F2E43094457FBE3261C15F01720F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Basis difference</header> 
<clause id="H7760977179F1454EB5E0BB95C158E19D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>basis difference</quote> means, with respect to any relevant foreign asset, the excess of—</text> 
<subclause id="HFB9049DBC39E4C8DA1240058DB938F9D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adjusted basis of such asset immediately after the covered asset acquisition, over</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F043F0B7BF84B379321C8AF1953682E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the adjusted basis of such asset immediately before the covered asset acquisition.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H14FE3E226C164F49AFD1CAB08DD3C2E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Built-in loss assets</header><text>In the case of a relevant foreign asset with respect to which the amount described in clause (i)(II) exceeds the amount described in clause (i)(I), such excess shall be taken into account under this subsection as a basis difference of a negative amount.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H26040569B40E45B7AB3458E4FF02AFBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special rule for section 338 elections</header><text>In the case of a covered asset acquisition described in paragraph (2)(A), the covered asset acquisition shall be treated for purposes of this subparagraph as occurring at the close of the acquisition date (as defined in section 338(h)(2)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC3D6C4C66BC45C6A27E6EA195401B79"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant foreign assets</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>relevant foreign asset</quote> means, with respect to any covered asset acquisition, any asset (including any goodwill, going concern value, or other intangible) with respect to such acquisition if income, deduction, gain, or loss attributable to such asset is taken into account in determining the foreign income tax referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62400D265D6743668FE0FDCCD6F0F0C3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign income tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>foreign income tax</quote> means any income, war profits, or excess profits tax paid or accrued to any foreign country or to any possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80AF525D67454DD08D20B673B270F9A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Taxes allowed as a deduction, etc</header><text>Sections 275 and 78 shall not apply to any tax which is not allowable as a credit under subsection (a) by reason of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D19A2F08A60420BBE870C6C4895944E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including to exempt from the application of this subsection certain covered asset acquisitions, and relevant foreign assets with respect to which the basis difference is de minimis.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC209BDEC1FA24B89A4EEF4DCD9F12D35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F2D961E83D243B6A34E20DE643B2FE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to covered asset acquisitions (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/901">section 901(m)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section) after December 31, 2010.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FC1A41F1EA04651AA756CF9C42224FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall not apply to any covered asset acquisition (as so defined) with respect to which the transferor and the transferee are not related if such acquisition is—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC6F090752DF4DFBBC01D5782D76A0C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made pursuant to a written agreement which was binding on January 1, 2011, and at all times thereafter,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7502869BFF94C0499282168747144C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>described in a ruling request submitted to the Internal Revenue Service on or before July 29, 2010, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F73526437F54252BE446E0A1D79BA06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>described on or before January 1, 2011, in a public announcement or in a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C7F688BAA5B48659CA8AD9FB83A8FAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a person shall be treated as related to another person if the relationship between such persons is described in section 267 or 707(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H5F33D8B3B398439BB2E91C64E96ABD44"><enum>213.</enum><header>Separate application of foreign tax credit limitation, etc., to items resourced under treaties</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H180ED7F49F4148AE9EC6505BE8D89459"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/904">section 904</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (7) and by inserting after paragraph (5) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2987F3B71DF403E83C7CCF2FDF0FE65" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1147D20906784351953E115444F268AC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Separate application to items resourced under treaties</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E0EAF0FF4E146F5AEAB41DDBC472B06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H82D05EA41CE743CAAA332A8AF7AEEBC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>without regard to any treaty obligation of the United States, any item of income would be treated as derived from sources within the United States,</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H14CC5E08E9954BBEA8B14D7E5987EC35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under a treaty obligation of the United States, such item would be treated as arising from sources outside the United States, and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H4C8F2D36E00549BCA2FCF9172B3ED99E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the taxpayer chooses the benefits of such treaty obligation,</text></clause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section and sections 902, 907, and 960 shall be applied separately with respect to each such item.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD08CC3DD6D2C4AEBB78E45093DE5912A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination with other provisions</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to any item of income to which subsection (h)(10) or section 865(h) applies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E7984DC3EA54E1596CB76C0405571CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this paragraph, including regulations or other guidance which provides that related items of income may be aggregated for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H4FE02A4667784FA68F7343C5EF343847"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E4E5BAF06D34694B99C03D151BAEF35" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>214.</enum><header>Limitation on the amount of foreign taxes deemed paid with respect to section 956 inclusions</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC75D03617FB843CD821D16C515B78B3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/960">Section 960</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2ECECDB9F86430B904C2299D96997E9" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H678B978DCBDE4A44952479899269D61E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation with respect to section 956 inclusions</header> 
<paragraph id="H5A5851FAC3F64D0C94BD7FD3CAE91FAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is included under section 951(a)(1)(B) in the gross income of a domestic corporation any amount attributable to the earnings and profits of a foreign corporation which is a member of a qualified group (as defined in section 902(b)) with respect to the domestic corporation, the amount of any foreign income taxes deemed to have been paid during the taxable year by such domestic corporation under section 902 by reason of subsection (a) with respect to such inclusion in gross income shall not exceed the amount of the foreign income taxes which would have been deemed to have been paid during the taxable year by such domestic corporation if cash in an amount equal to the amount of such inclusion in gross income were distributed as a series of distributions (determined without regard to any foreign taxes which would be imposed on an actual distribution) through the chain of ownership which begins with such foreign corporation and ends with such domestic corporation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65DB0E3132294A678FB66D440EC09234"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to prevent abuse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including regulations or other guidance which prevent the inappropriate use of the foreign corporation’s foreign income taxes not deemed paid by reason of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E3E021ABC034BD5B3C645BD0365E211"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to acquisitions of United States property (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/956">section 956(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) after December 31, 2010.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCBB3360C47A4A89BCD5D7AE2F852FDE"><enum>215.</enum><header>Special rule with respect to certain redemptions by foreign subsidiaries</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0DDF8A60AB1A438796CA33DCF9592DBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (5) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/304">section 304(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C) and by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7899FDA3D9144CE6B18148CDF645A731" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H0A193A76F4F444E782A43CDBD25BAF8D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule in case of foreign acquiring corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any acquisition to which subsection (a) applies in which the acquiring corporation is a foreign corporation, no earnings and profits shall be taken into account under paragraph (2)(A) (and subparagraph (A) shall not apply) if more than 50 percent of the dividends arising from such acquisition (determined without regard to this subparagraph) would neither—</text> 
<clause id="H16ACBA0E946044948257159AC493B0A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be subject to tax under this chapter for the taxable year in which the dividends arise, nor</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE5948D9122D948E6B9B6221950854192"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be includible in the earnings and profits of a controlled foreign corporation (as defined in section 957 and without regard to section 953(c)).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H201FC3A674F4493BAB183C9D89128DC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to acquisitions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF5A6F38082894C9D8C3DB77AD869DDBA"><enum>216.</enum><header>Modification of affiliation rules for purposes of rules allocating interest expense</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBCE35830063943BAAF2E6B79B20E3CC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/864">section 864(e)(5)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEE4B03F34DEA4494AC463493CA9955B4" style="OLC"><text>Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a foreign corporation shall be treated as a member of the affiliated group if—</text> 
<clause id="HF8E80A691FA14541ABD12B14FF44BFBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 50 percent of the gross income of such foreign corporation for the taxable year is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE83B50C6145B498E9E4E0D64DFFA3E0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 80 percent of either the vote or value of all outstanding stock of such foreign corporation is owned directly or indirectly by members of the affiliated group (determined with regard to this sentence).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF5E3F46D1F64642AA5AB51F6C89506D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51FD6E5D3E44402D8786FB8DD65ACC6F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>217.</enum><header>Termination of special rules for interest and dividends received from persons meeting the 80-percent foreign business requirements</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCF7DD5CC88F94FABAE75CFACDFBFF60C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/861">section 861(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (A) and by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFD4BDD6927B4491A4EA6F05A794F08C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grandfather rule with respect To withholding on interest and dividends received from persons meeting the 80-percent foreign business requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HC2C8A0E1234F45FFB3B89EC2C9D14F7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/871">section 871(i)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5D375A80BD0442BB691C05496A62AB6" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HC0C0E020982041638601C723627712DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The active foreign business percentage of—</text> 
<clause id="HE995B539602B40FFB3BE2B1D31EFA3DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any dividend paid by an existing 80/20 company, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD9B6F06094A2459AADD1C523D53A7941"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any interest paid by an existing 80/20 company.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D7AD057660F46A99EF34017696CA039"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>Section 871 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsections (l) and (m) as subsections (m) and (n), respectively, and by inserting after subsection (k) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96D3B17F0A7F4181A1C08E0FC98CA582" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HEC4B27AE0B514F3C821A0250721558F6"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Rules relating to existing 80/20 companies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection and subsection (i)(2)(B)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B4A97AC323E4B729D2D8485558D8A70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing 80/20 company</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6BC737F72018436495BE46539A00836C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>existing 80/20 company</quote> means any corporation if—</text> 
<clause id="H6A06C26E2A254BD79EB4DE246CF28D95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such corporation met the 80-percent foreign business requirements of section 861(c)(1) (as in effect before the date of the enactment of this subsection) for such corporation’s last taxable year beginning before January 1, 2011,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H14D577A4019A4B0A9F07D1686F4D5CE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such corporation meets the 80-percent foreign business requirements of subparagraph (B) with respect to each taxable year after the taxable year referred to in clause (i), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H957E599708FB458C9D7F97CF11472434"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>there has not been an addition of a substantial line of business with respect to such corporation after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93474689D6A0476CA8D2CA464B9C2F4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign business requirements</header> 
<clause id="H9232257334634E5A94B9F9074903B98A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iv), a corporation meets the 80-percent foreign business requirements of this subparagraph if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Secretary that at least 80 percent of the gross income from all sources of such corporation for the testing period is active foreign business income.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7D1A309D01BA45EE8F37FC3F19A9D7F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Active foreign business income</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <quote>active foreign business income</quote> means gross income which—</text> 
<subclause id="HCCBD78ADC60E4A6DBCB2FF0167E157E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is derived from sources outside the United States (as determined under this subchapter), and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H15B24459A2B84423AEB8484CFF4A4161"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is attributable to the active conduct of a trade or business in a foreign country or possession of the United States.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H0B57867B99A949F7A418C06CCD9E4E74"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Testing period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>testing period</quote> means the 3-year period ending with the close of the taxable year of the corporation preceding the payment (or such part of such period as may be applicable). If the corporation has no gross income for such 3-year period (or part thereof), the testing period shall be the taxable year in which the payment is made.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H870B63F500E449A89EF4EBDBD534C0FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>In the case of a taxable year for which the testing period includes 1 or more taxable years beginning before January 1, 2011—</text> 
<subclause id="H436EDAA28F1B489BB784F95561B0A94E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a corporation meets the 80-percent foreign business requirements of this subparagraph if and only if the weighted average of—</text> 
<item id="HD07355D1A23E423C919B6C25390B6BD2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the percentage of the corporation's gross income from all sources that is active foreign business income (as defined in subparagraph (B) of section 861(c)(1) (as in effect before the date of the enactment of this subsection)) for the portion of the testing period that includes taxable years beginning before January 1, 2011, and</text></item> 
<item id="HF4989F57E16A49B6B3A0092487900F4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the percentage of the corporation's gross income from all sources that is active foreign business income (as defined in clause (ii) of this subparagraph) for the portion of the testing period, if any, that includes taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2011,</text></item><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">is at least 80 percent, and</continuation-text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1A4F447256D94333AFA348B61CE21479"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the active foreign business percentage for such taxable year shall equal the weighted average percentage determined under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8894030779924BAF9AA4BC6E56DA8C4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Active foreign business percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (1)(B)(iv), the term <quote>active foreign business percentage</quote> means, with respect to any existing 80/20 company, the percentage which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC945E34B7EFF484AA41F47A626F97751"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the active foreign business income of such company for the testing period, is of</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB251612C10B42BF8D1D53C337245D51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the gross income of such company for the testing period from all sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H501E5FA2B11C4FD6BB2DBDA1AA353988"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying paragraph (1) (other than subparagraphs (A)(i) and (B)(iv) thereof) and paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0BEB974DBBC54AFA97EEBDF3A2C32577"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The corporation referred to in paragraph (1)(A) and all of such corporation’s subsidiaries shall be treated as one corporation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BA150E9523948609F208A5F0E26B842"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsidiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>subsidiary</quote> means any corporation in which the corporation referred to in subparagraph (A) owns (directly or indirectly) stock meeting the requirements of section 1504(a)(2) (determined by substituting <quote>50 percent</quote> for <quote>80 percent</quote> each place it appears and without regard to section 1504(b)(3)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9517186F469B43C799269F45053F8B55"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance which provide for the proper application of the aggregation rules described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB124FB0ACDD4CDE89991814EAC99A5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H0EA43EA70CA44C56B0D840F91F0C6CAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/861">Section 861</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsection (c) and by redesignating subsections (d), (e), and (f) as subsections (c), (d), and (e), respectively.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H101548A37EAF4BC4B1897EBCF774FED7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (9) of section 904(h) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9334639F192245F7A68A38FBE0BBF246" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H020FE3000B87444A92F303EB0424647F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Treatment of certain domestic corporations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any dividend treated as not from sources within the United States under section 861(a)(2)(A), the corporation paying such dividend shall be treated for purposes of this subsection as a United States-owned foreign corporation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H596DF63DD1B54A11A4650BA87BB339FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subsection (c) of section 2104 of such Code is amended in the last sentence by striking <quote>or to a debt obligation of a domestic corporation</quote> and all that follows and inserting a period.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD49912BEFCD844D482D86F9B143C6E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="H926E0630EEF1489E9006759DB86DD248"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6D01990E8024C73BD1F166E57990012"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grandfather rule for outstanding debt obligations</header> 
<subparagraph id="H37D44C2F5F9F4998A0B649A53033D044"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall not apply to payments of interest on obligations issued before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AD7801E3E4645ADBA3EB20C6A622F28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for related party debt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any interest which is payable to a related person (determined under rules similar to the rules of section 954(d)(3)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0A2CB4A949446D98D97BF562A2631C2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Significant modifications treated as new issues</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a significant modification of the terms of any obligation (including any extension of the term of such obligation) shall be treated as a new issue.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H429498FD77DA47F3A76C402BA76B4685"><enum>218.</enum><header>Limitation on extension of statute of limitations for failure to notify Secretary of certain foreign transfers</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H00D9AE52817D41B6B855CF42903E5E53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (8) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6501">section 6501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H81FFB04D033C4E948ED96C822D6B659F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the case of any information</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35EC0DC3E33D4848AB17238BFDED02F8" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HA24315A0004E42F1A897189D8B78A15F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any information</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H595952783D1F421BA505A33B292A13C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A4B866C458F4E56BCABA91F0AC79375" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H7B4D2A18813E4748870433B2EBF6258D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application to failures due to reasonable cause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the failure to furnish the information referred to in subparagraph (A) is due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect, subparagraph (A) shall apply only to the item or items related to such failure.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5CD04FFD8D2407AA812739DDCAEA45B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect as if included in section 513 of the Hiring Incentives to Restore Employment Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0EECBE7F007A4BC59DFE9FDA95C91FE0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>219.</enum><header>Elimination of advance refundability of earned income credit</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H836723579C5C4ED193B935D0984D7341"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 are repealed:</text> 
<paragraph id="H274BC0CCA6474226A4CC8991DA454E58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3507.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4041557794140CDAF69300F1E786F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (g) of section 32.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3D71368AF744EF9B6A31A57EA87C996"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (7) of section 6051(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9C201784E0E433A9B0BABF2F74A8E40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H103B37BF0D454F9EA38E77C97F7625B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6012">Section 6012(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking paragraph (8) and by redesignating paragraph (9) as paragraph (8).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C29B6A8CE7A4EAFA50D98BA62E57D69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 6302 of such Code is amended by striking subsection (i).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8381E6D7A643474BA3D4C20C7FCDEFF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for chapter 25 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 3507.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5189A4DE0B204A23853AE140DBAE63AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The repeals and amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2010.</text></subsection></section></subtitle></title> 
<title id="H0AA0448078AD47DF932E97B60FD094FF"><enum>III</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Rescissions</header> 
<section id="H37B23949402944419351460B0D77B9FB"><enum>301.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is rescinded from accounts under the heading <quote>Department of Agriculture—Rural Development</quote>, $122,000,000, to be derived from the unobligated balances of funds that were provided for such accounts in prior appropriation Acts (other than <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) and that were designated by the Congress in such Acts as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="HE3F04265520C45D89B778BF30DC2FC75"><enum>302.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>Department of Commerce—National Telecommunications and Information Administration—Broadband Technology Opportunities Program</quote> in title II of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $302,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE47C758CD84E48BE9BA060E203660BF3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>303.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated in Department of Defense Appropriations Acts, the following funds are rescinded from the following accounts in the specified amounts:</text><list level="paragraph" list-type="none"><list-item><quote>Aircraft Procurement, Army, 2008/2010</quote>, $21,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Procurement of Weapons and Tracked Combat Vehicles, Army, 2008/2010</quote>, $21,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Procurement of Ammunition, Army, 2008/2010</quote>, $17,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Other Procurement, Army, 2008/2010</quote>, $75,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Weapons Procurement, Navy, 2008/2010</quote>, $26,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Other Procurement, Navy, 2008/2010</quote>, $42,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Procurement, Marine Corps, 2008/2010</quote>, $13,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Aircraft Procurement, Air Force, 2008/2010</quote>, $102,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Missile Procurement, Air Force, 2008/2010</quote>, $28,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Procurement of Ammunition, Air Force, 2008/2010</quote>, $7,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Other Procurement, Air Force, 2008/2010</quote>, $130,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Procurement, Defense-Wide, 2008/2010</quote>, $33,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Research, Development, Test and Evaluation, Army, 2009/2010</quote>, $76,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Research, Development, Test and Evaluation, Air Force, 2009/2010</quote>, $164,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Research, Development, Test and Evaluation, Defense-Wide, 2009/2010</quote>, $137,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation, Test and Evaluation, Defense, 2009/2010</quote>, $1,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army, 2010</quote>, $154,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy, 2010</quote>, $155,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps, 2010</quote>, $25,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force, 2010</quote>, $155,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Defense-Wide, 2010</quote>, $126,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army Reserve, 2010</quote>, $12,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy Reserve, 2010</quote>, $6,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps Reserve, 2010</quote>, $1,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force Reserve, 2010</quote>, $14,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army National Guard, 2010</quote>, $28,000,000; and</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air National Guard, 2010</quote>, $27,000,000.</list-item></list></section> 
<section id="H8A5B9EF65918477E9872D70D1D2594AA"><enum>304.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H56416F89206649F9AF07835C0CF05E0C"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated in the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>), the following funds are rescinded from the following accounts in the specified amounts:</text><list level="paragraph" list-type="none"><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army, 2009/2010</quote>, $113,500,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy, 2009/2010</quote>, $34,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps, 2009/2010</quote>, $7,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force, 2009/2010</quote>, $61,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army Reserve, 2009/2010</quote>, $3,500,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy Reserve, 2009/2010</quote>, $8,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps Reserve, 2009/2010</quote>, $1,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force Reserve, 2009/2010</quote>, $2,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army National Guard, 2009/2010</quote>, $1,000,000;</list-item><list-item><quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air National Guard, 2009/2010</quote>, $2,500,000; and</list-item><list-item><quote>Defense Health Program, 2009/2010</quote>, $27,000,000.</list-item></list></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44E40A3B582B4159ABADDA133A4249C2"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated in the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/252">Public Law 110–252</external-xref>), the following funds are rescinded from the following account in the specified amount:</text><list level="paragraph" list-type="none"><list-item><quote>Procurement, Marine Corps, 2009/2011</quote>, $122,000,000.</list-item></list></subsection></section> 
<section id="H787E5CC0C12948EB872CC3A51D460E2A"><enum>305.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1386CC7C7D78418FA3CFB4E9FB5BCC0E"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated for <quote>Procurement of Weapons and Tracked Combat Vehicles, Army</quote> in title III of division A of public Law 111–118, $116,000,000 are rescinded.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0871E2144494E51BEFE360E6545AB9E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Of the funds appropriated for <quote>Other Procurement, Army</quote> in title III of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/329">Public Law 110–329</external-xref>, $87,000,000 are rescinded.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H46153B42F9B243BB84E68A54B9BEAD69"><enum>306.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are rescinded the following amounts from the specified accounts:</text> 
<paragraph id="H36A0C6024EA144F5ADEE160C19FFB812"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$20,000,000, to be derived from unobligated balances of funds made available in prior appropriations Acts under the heading <quote>Department of Energy—Nuclear Energy</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBBA5EAEF8CEF46509EBDC1EFD747FCB8"><enum>307.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances of funds provided under the heading <quote>Nuclear Regulatory Commission</quote> in prior appropriations Acts, $18,000,000 is permanently rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H79274853BB5442178284A9295698AF5F"><enum>308.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for “Department of Energy—Title 17—Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program” in title III of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $1,500,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H86E1EB018378459FB5A2A1D52EE135EA"><enum>309.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are permanently rescinded from <quote>General Services Administration—Real Property Activities—Federal Building Fund</quote>, $75,000,000 from Rental of Space and $25,000,000 from Building Operations, to be derived from unobligated balances that were provided in previous appropriations Acts.</text></section> 
<section id="HCC9B42787ABC47939D5B4867EDA127C5"><enum>310.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>Bureau of Indian Affairs—Indian Guaranteed Loan Program Account</quote> in title VII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $6,820,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H3D13578A8AD542D0BE1C62F8B2E81BA8"><enum>311.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>Environmental Protection Agency—Hazardous Substance Superfund</quote> in title VII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $2,600,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FE4D339A10148CCB01CBDA7AEF8D7F9"><enum>312.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>Environmental Protection Agency—Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund Program</quote> in title VII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $9,200,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H0DFE88443B3048C4A533370EA35C28D5"><enum>313.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for transfer in title VII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, “Environmental Protection Agency—Environmental Programs and Management”, $10,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="HEB67A47BEB0D480E97CE36D1977B4364"><enum>314.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>National Park Service—Construction</quote> in chapter 7 of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/324">Public Law 108–324</external-xref>, $4,800,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H5C62DB20E0914FFE9F549DB9630839A1"><enum>315.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>National Park Service—Construction</quote> in chapter 5 of title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/234">Public Law 109–234</external-xref>, $6,400,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H8504FD52FC2E44ECBED6AB8722713D8A"><enum>316.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for <quote>Fish and Wildlife Service—Construction</quote> in chapter 6 of title I of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/329">Public Law 110–329</external-xref>, $3,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE93993FA4F144FF39855F81D9519E9CF"><enum>317.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balance of funds appropriated in the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/333">Public Law 103–333</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 2574) under the heading <quote>Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund</quote> is rescinded.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1347AF591A349EC9E73777C8E3267CA"><enum>318.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated for the Commissioner of Social Security under section 2201(e)(2)(B) in title II of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $47,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7FD0920C5974398B30344B1BA7AA670"><enum>319.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated in part VI of subtitle I of title II of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, $110,000,000 are rescinded, to be derived only from the amount provided under section 1899K(b) of such title.</text></section> 
<section id="H2D104EEAC52A4F1A87AF9BF5E2C731CA"><enum>320.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated for “Department of Education—Education for the Disadvantaged” in division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>, $50,000,000 are rescinded, to be derived only from the amount provided for a comprehensive literacy development and education program under section 1502 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></section> 
<section id="H8A9F5BB4FA2B46FD8EF1AD067097DBD0"><enum>321.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated for “Department of Education—Student Aid Administration” in division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>, $82,000,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="HC0363F3A8C964CE3AE230C20B7FD199B"><enum>322.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated for “Department of Education—Innovation and Improvement” in division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref>, $10,700,000 are rescinded, to be derived only from the amount provided to carry out subpart 8 of part D of title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></section> 
<section id="HD0D9C0ED19E94C8B9F340BD8DD9A7997"><enum>323.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under <quote>Department of Defense, Military Construction, Army</quote> from prior appropriations Acts, $340,000,000 is rescinded: 
<proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no funds may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement or as appropriations for overseas deployments and other activities pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="H93507D8934E54CA88D0EEA30293E112B"><enum>324.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under <quote>Department of Defense, Military Construction, Navy and Marine Corps</quote> from prior appropriations Acts, $110,000,000 is rescinded: 
<proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no funds may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement or as appropriations for overseas deployments and other activities pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="HB64D2E37F5E843969CFF4A718C772B6D"><enum>325.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under <quote>Department of Defense, Military Construction, Air Force</quote> from prior appropriations Acts, $50,000,000 is rescinded: 
<proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That no funds may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement or as appropriations for overseas deployments and other activities pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></section> 
<section id="HD4D7333D855740058DB1D29334DF32C8"><enum>326.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for the General Operating Expenses account of the Department of Veterans Affairs in section 2201(e)(4)(A)(ii) of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref> (123 Stat. 454; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6428">26 U.S.C. 6428</external-xref> note), $6,100,000 are rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="HB40AB3C7EF63400EA94260E038A12247"><enum>327.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available by title X of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>, the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, under the heading “ Departmental Administration, Information Technology Systems” $5,000,000 is hereby rescinded.</text></section> 
<section id="H0949F7CA2CDF42809CDB5DF3AD28A016"><enum>328.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2C5C6869E1DB46C2B400AEEF8A9ABB0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Millennium challenge corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under the heading <quote>Millennium Challenge Corporation</quote> in title III of division H of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref> and under such heading in prior Acts making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs, $50,000,000 are rescinded.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34B0050ACDC0441B9259432319137A89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civilian stabilization initiative</header> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63708D61CBB1481ABBAA962D438CDF4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under the heading <quote>Department of State—Administration of Foreign Affairs—Civilian Stabilization Initiative</quote> in prior Acts making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs, $40,000,000 are rescinded.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D1CCA341DC6464B8777D5F2031E20F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United states agency for international development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available under the heading <quote>United States Agency for International Development—Funds Appropriated to the President—Civilian Stabilization Initiative</quote> in prior Acts making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs, $30,000,000 are rescinded.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD731BE1121A64B98AB2B9DC2304C18DA"><enum>329.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are rescinded the following amounts from the specified accounts:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H484A2F59FED54652AB882A85D32A4546"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">“Department of Transportation—Federal Aviation Administration—Facilities and Equipment”, $2,182,544, to be derived from unobligated balances made available under this heading in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/324">Public Law 108–324</external-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H653863C3C5204925A32D40A94BEA0426"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">“Department of Transportation—Federal Aviation Administration—Facilities and Equipment”, $5,705,750, to be derived from unobligated balances made available under this heading in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF65B4DE24A9C40E29FF9EC72940120FC"><enum>330.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances of funds apportioned to each State under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, $2,200,000,000 are permanently rescinded: 
<proviso><italic>Provided</italic>,</proviso> That such rescission shall be distributed among the States in the same proportion as the funds subject to such rescission were apportioned to the States for fiscal year 2009: 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic>,</proviso> That such rescission shall not apply to the funds distributed in accordance with sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/130">130(f)</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/23/104">104(b)(5)</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code; sections 133(d)(1) and 163 of such title, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/59">Public Law 109–59</external-xref>; and the first sentence of section 133(d)(3)(A) of such title: 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic>,</proviso> That notwithstanding section 1132 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/140">Public Law 110–140</external-xref>, in administering the rescission required under this heading, the Secretary of Transportation shall allow each State to determine the amount of the required rescission to be drawn from the programs to which the rescission applies.</text></section></title> 
<title id="H7DB6D0E1CA084BD0A4C5852B64275296"><enum>IV</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Budgetary provisions</header> 
<section id="H8458883C2A094AC78FCCAC9860FFE355"><enum>401.</enum><header>Budgetary provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, jointly submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairmen of the House and Senate Budget Committees, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage in the House acting first on this conference report or amendment between the Houses.</text></section></title> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
</bill> 


